LAI TAK YI

Software Engineer

write

byronlai@gmail.com

call

(852) 6675 4494

blog

byronlai.com

GitHub github.com/byronlai

EXPERIENCE

IBM

Software Engineer (Placement)

2012 - 2013

I worked with a small team to enhance the user experience, functionalities and accessibility of IBM iNotes. I also helped other teams to modernize

legacy codebase.

CUHK

Software Engineer

2014 - 2015

I worked with educators from top universities in Hong Kong to help create a new online learning platform that will be used by thousands of local

tertiary students.

EDUCATION

2010 - 2014

The Chinese University of Hong Kong

B.S. in Computer Science, First-Class Honours

Ko Ho Ning Scholarship 2011 - 2012 Dean's List 2012 - 2013, 2013 - 2014

PUBLICATION

IBM developerWorks

Lock-free Data Structures in Java

July 2008

An article discussing the implementation of lock-free (non-blocking) data structures using CAS (compare and swap) in Java to allow concurrent

access without the use of mutexes

PROJECTS

Hunter vs Monsters

A first-person shooter game with Unity3D as the game engine

Lock-free Structures

Lock-free (non-blocking) stack and linked list implemented in Java

bit.ly/1UpljnP

wcwidth() for OS X

A wcwidth() implementation support-

ing the latest version of Unicode

C Binary Indexed Tree

Binary indexed tree implemented in C for finding prefix sums efficiently

bit.ly/1RYNE7M

UTF Transcoder

Streaming UTF-8 and UTF-16 transcoders implemented in Swift

C++ Gap Buffer

C++ gap buffer implementation for efficient clustered operations

SUMMARY

I'm a 25 years old software developer based in Hong Kong. I learned programming when I was 13 and was then traditionally-trained in the university.

I love everything that has to do with system design, product design and I feel a true devotion for algorithms. I also enjoy building things that help others and benefit the community.

LANGUAGES

English

Cantonese

Mandarin

SKILLS

UNIX Programming

C/C++, POSIX API, GNU Make

Scripting

Bash, Python, Ruby

Web Development

SQL, HTML, CSS, JS, Responsive, Rails

Tools

Git, Vim, Bison, Flex

Methodologies

Test-driven Development

Agile Software Development

Object-oriented Programming